

Tiago Pessoa

OFTWARE ENGINEER · FRONT END EXPERT

Oporto, Portugal

■ tiagopessoa123@hotmail.com | 😭 www.tpessoa.online | 🖸 tpessoa | 🛅 tpessoa

Work Experience

Critical Techworks (BMW Group)

Oporto, Portugal

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Set. 2021 - Current

- Developed and maintained one of BMW claim management front-end web applications adding core features align with stakeholder's needs.
- · Collaborated with designers and back-end developers to guarantee a seamless user experience and requirements accomplishment.
- Consistently performed **automated testing** to certify the highest level of quality assurance.
- · Conducted code reviews and provided constructive feedback to improve code quality and maintainability
- Operated under a **SCRUM** framework utilizing **Agile** methodologies and actively participated in technical discussions to provide solutions that aligned with business requirements.
- Performed **production monitoring** to analyze logging data and report any issues through appropriate channels.

Jean Monnet Centre of Excellence

Coimbra, Portugal

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERNSHIP

Set. 2020 - Jul.2021

- Designed and implemented a didactic platform for hosting European Union (EU) activities, in addition to conceptualizing and producing educational board games. More info on my GitHub.
- Tech Stack utilized: React, Node, Express, Mongodb and Docker.

Skills_

Front-end Next.js, React, Angular, Typescript, HTML5, CSS, Tailwind CSS

Back-end Node.js, Express, tRPC, REST API **Database** Prisma, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Automated testing Jest, Cypress

Others SCRUM, Agile, Design Systems, Responsive web design, Git, GitHub Actions

I showcase my skills and ongoing learning on my personal website, where I feature examples of my latest projects and accomplishments.

Education

University of Coimbra

Coimbra, Portugal

MASTER IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

2019 - 2021

Had the opportunity to apply the fundamental principles I learned through a comprehensive final project. This project covered all stages of software development, including risk management, agile methodology, requirements gathering, architectural design, testing, and more. I was able to demonstrate my understanding of the full software development life cycle, from inception to delivery, by thoroughly documenting each step along the way.

University of Coimbra Coimbra Coimbra, Portugal

BACHELOR IN INFORMATICS ENGINEERING

2016 - 2019

I had the chance to work with different programming languages and tackle a variety of projects, which helped me develop a strong sense of data structures and problem-solving and gave me a broad range of experience in computer science.

About Me_

I am a Software Engineer with 3 years of experience and a strong interest in web development. Currently, my expertise is more directed towards **front-end** development, although I am always interested in the full lifecycle of a product along with understanding the business.

My approach to work involves deep commitment and drive, as well as continuously seeking new learning opportunities to enhance my skills both as a developer and as an individual.

TIAGO PESSOA 1